pbase.com 2019-03-17

# Privacy Policy - PBase Help System

We think protecting privacy is really important. You should know that we are not in the business of selling or sharing information. We use the information we collect to help make PBase the best photo site for serious photographers on the Internet. By visiting and using PBase.com you consent the terms of this privacy agreement. We may change the PBase Privacy Policy from time to time, so please check back often. 

## What is a privacy policy and what does it cover?

This privacy policy covers how PBase.com LLC (“PBase,” “we,” “us,” “ours”) treats personal information that it collects and receives, including information related to your use of PBase services. 

Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that PBase does not own or control, or to people that PBase does not employ or manage. 

## How does PBase collect and use my information? 

### General 

We may collect personal information when you register, when you use our services, when you visit our pages or the pages related to the content contained within the PBase site. In order to understand our customers better, we may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. 

When you register we ask for information such as your first and last name and email address. We may request information about your address, occupation, industry, etc. Once you register with PBase and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us. 

On your [account page](http://www.pbase.com/account) you control how you will be identified to other users on the site itself, and whether or not you wish to display an email address and location in connection with your gallery. If you choose to make that information available, it will be publicly accessible to anyone who visits our site, which may include automated programs called “spambots” that collect email addresses on behalf of companies not affiliated with PBase. 

If you use forums or chat features on our site, please be aware that any personally identifiable information you post can be read, collected, or used by other visitors to the site, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for information you choose to submit in these forums.

If you sell products through the PBase site, we may be required to request and store your social security number or comparable id number in order to comply with IRS reporting requirements. 

We collect information about your transactions with us and your use of the services that we offer. 

We automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, browser settings, and pages requested. We also require a cookie, used only to keep track of your login status. 

We use information for the following general purposes: 

  * To fulfill your requests for products and services
  * To improve our services
  * To contact you, conduct research, and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients
  * To promote new products and services from PBase and its trusted partners

### Use by Children

Our site is not designed to be used by children under the age of 13, but we do not collect and monitor the date of birth of individuals who register on PBase. If you are under the age of 18, please obtain parental consent before creating an account on the site. Per the requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), we will not knowingly collect and retain personal information from individuals under 13. 

## Will PBase share or sell my email address or other information? 

We do NOT rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:   

  1. We provide the information to trusted partners who work on our behalf of or with us under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to fulfill products or services you have purchased or to help us communicate with you about offers from us and our marketing partners. These companies do not have any independent right to share this information. 
  2. We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal processes, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  3. We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our [terms of service](http://www.pbase.com/help/tos), or as otherwise required by law. 
  4. We transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, we will notify you before transferring information about you and before your information becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

If you choose to use a referral link on our site to tell a friend about PBase, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address, then automatically send the friend an email inviting him or her to visit PBase. This is a one-time email and PBase stores the information solely for the purpose of tracking. The recipient may contact us at [privacy@pbase.com](mailto:privacy@pbase.com) to request that we remove the information from our database. 

### Cookies 

PBase will set and access both a session ID cookie and a persistent cookie on your computer. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer by your browser at the request of a Web. We use the persistent cookie to keep you logged in, record your preferences, and to monitor general data about traffic and visitors. The session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A third-party service may also set a cookie on your computer to track traffic and user data anonymously. This cookie will not track or store any personally identifiable information about you. 

You can find instructions for removing persistent cookies from your hard drive by following the directions in your Internet browser's "help" file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of the site may be limited.

## How can I edit or delete my PBase account information and preferences? 

### General 

You can edit your account information, including any personal data we have stored, at any time by going to your [account page](http://www.pbase.com/account).   
While we will give you the ability to opt-out of certain types of marketing communications, there are some communications from us, such as service announcements, administrative messages and the PBase Newsletter, that are considered part of PBase membership and you may not opt out of receiving them. 

You may delete your PBase account by contacting support at [support@pbase.com](mailto:support@pbase.com), or writing to us at: 

     PBase   
Customer Care - Privacy Policy Issues   
PO Box 13585   
Research Triangle Park, NC 27709   
USA   

If you have photos or images on PBase, that material may remain in some form on the site even after you retire it from public view, particularly if you have granted permission for it to be used as part of a collaborative project that exists elsewhere on the site. 

## What security measures does PBase use?

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. 

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you. While we make every effort to establish security measures to prevent loss and abuse of personal information under our control, we cannot guarantee the protection of information against illegal, unauthorized acts or accidents. 

Your PBase account information is password-protected. You are responsible for not sharing your password and for choosing a good password. You are responsible for the use of the site by anyone using your login and password, and should notify us immediately if the information has been misappropriated or stolen. 

In certain areas we use industry-standard Secure-Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption to protect data transmissions related to commerce, and for billing information we store. 

## Will your privacy policy change? 

We may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your PBase account, updating this privacy policy, and/or by placing a prominent notice on our site. 

### Questions and Suggestions 

If you have questions or suggestions, contact us by emailing [support@pbase.com](mailto:support@pbase.com) or at:   

     PBase  
Customer Care - Privacy Policy Issues  
PO Box 13585  
Research Triangle Park, NC 27709  
USA   

[Click here](http://www.pbase.com/contact.html) for contact information.   
Last updated 01-Nov-2006.
